Yeah, I hear you on that.
I mean, here in the US if like, I used
to wake up at like five, like I would stay up all night.
Yeah. And then it would just be,
I would have no more time in the day.
Um, yeah. Yeah. It's funny.
I would like, so typically my days are likes I'm, I'm up
for about like 17 hours.
Um, which is, I, it's like a lot, you know, you're,
you're trying to Yeah.
Trying to maximize every, every minute of the day.
But I realize like the amount of time
I've actually like I actually work is actually not
that it's, it's not even, I would say even eight hours
of time that I actually work. Yeah.
And for me, I feel like,
but it's also the, I feel like this is a problem
with working online as well, is when you go to a office,
you, you know, you are there for a certain amount of time,
it's easy to keep track of it,
but when you are working on your computer by yourself Yeah.
It's like you are counting just productive hours, like
where you are constantly working.
You don't count in breaks and stuff. Yeah. So, yeah.
Even for me, it's, I don't think it's eight hours,
but every day I feel like, oh, I work a lot.
Yeah, for sure. If I was
to track it, it's not this here.
Yeah. I hear you. I wanna touch on that in a little bit.
I just wanna say hi to Brayley. What's up B Brayley.
Can you hear us?
Yeah, I hear you. Amazing. How's it going, man?
Where are you calling from?
Uh, I'm just listening off
what their questions so I can learn.
Uh, so by the way, I'm new here.
Welcome in your cars. Welcome man. Are you? Thank you.
Where are you from? Uh, country-wise?
Uh, I'm from Philippines. Oh, nice.
Oh. Um,
my Tagalog is really bad, so I'm not gonna try to try,
but I can, I can understand.
Yeah. Did
You and do you visit sometimes in Philippines, John?
Uh, we actually went last year in December.
Um, we visited our team and then mm-Hmm.
Um, I visited family as well,
but I hadn't been in like 15 years, so, oh.
It was a new experience for me going back a second
time. Yeah, definitely.
So you are my family on Philippines.
Yeah. I mean, my parents, you know, they immigrated here.
So I'm first generation US born. Oh.
But, you know, 90% of my family's out there.
My dad has like 11 brothers and sisters.
My mom has, you know, I have a huge family,
but I'm kind of a, I think that was the part
that I missed out on a lot being, or like being us born.
I didn't have a huge family to grow up with. Yeah.
And, uh, also, yeah,
You're Filipino.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. No, I'm full Filipino. Mm-Hmm.
Yeah. Alright, that's
Good. And yeah, so
I, you know,
but I, I grew up very westernized, very American,
but I grew up in a very Filipino household, you know,
spoke Tagalog and ate Filipino food and all this stuff.
Um, so I think that was one of the hardest things
for me growing up, was like the two cultures.
You know, like, I, I was, I,
I ne I didn't have a Filipino friend until,
I don't know, like high school.
So there was, there was no Filipinos around me. All right.
Um, so I wasn't able to really like, tap into the culture
like I was always at, okay, I do I wanna be American,
or do I wanna be Filipino?
It's like I kept resisting one or the other.
It was interesting. Um, but anyways.
Yeah. Have you guys ever been us
Especially? No.
It's, it's super difficult to have a visa to the us.
It's hard to get here, huh? Yeah.
Yeah. Um, yeah, I feel like, I don't know.
I don't know why they make it so hard,
but it's, I would love for you to, if you were
to visit anytime, you
Know? Yeah. Like, me and my
girlfriend, we wanted to visit.
And for, even for her, she's from France,
and even for her,
the waiting period is more than a year
after you apply. It's crazy.
Like a wait list. Yeah.
It's, it's not like we're that busy.
Um, well, awesome guys.
I, I really wanted to kind of circle back to
what we're talking about, uh, with regards to productivity.
I think that's something, um, not really talked about
so much as a creative, at least like in our course.
Um, I mean, we do a little bit,
but I would love to kind of hear like,
what's optimal for everybody.
Uh, Braley feel free to add, you know, your your experience
to this, but Yeah, like, changing my schedule
to be more optimized has been like a game changer.
Um, like prioritizing sleep
is, is like a, a really big thing for me.
Um, I know in the past when I was like, working really,
really late hours sleep would be the last
thing I would care about. It would just be like,
Yeah.
Is that what's happening right now for you? Sparse. Yeah.
Yeah. But I've slowly started to move on to like,
it's always this hustle mindset that, oh,
if I have the work, I can't say no to it, you know?
Yeah. It's kinda like if I work coming into my business,
I'm like, okay, even if I have to sacrifice some sleep, I,
it affects your personal relationships
or commitments as well sometimes.
Mm-Hmm. And it's, it's a constant cycle.
Like, it's hard to get out of this and Yeah.
But I've slowly started to move on to, okay, I want
to prioritize things that I like working on.
I like to, I want to prioritize things
that I'm enjoying to do.
Mm-Hmm. Rather than the volume to say.
I think that's super important. And I think it's,
uh, yeah.
It's, uh, to, for creatives, I feel like
to be doing this, it's a recipe for burnout.
Like, you burn out super quick doing this, I feel like.
Yeah. And like, I think if, even if you do it for a month,
then you burn out for two weeks, it, it is still kind
of balanced if you are consistent, not working too,
too much, but a decent amount all the time
and not burning out.
I think it's both the same.
Oh yeah. I've had, uh, a lot of burnout, uh, experiences.
Uh, brayley how about you, man?
How's your, like, productivity look like?
Yeah. Uh, for me, uh, I think,
uh, I wanna grind so much.
I, I, I wanna learn about this, uh,
editing stuff because I am new here.
It's, it's been 10 months, I think, since I
will show this career and continue growing.
So, are you, um, are you editing, um,
like what's your current position right now?
Are you editing video ads? Uh,
Yeah. Video ads for
e-commerce friends.
Perfect. So you've been doing it for 10 months?
Yeah, 10 months. Awesome. Oh, 11 months since January.
Perfect. And what was your background before that?
Uh, I'm a student, college student, and then I drop out.
Thanks. Um, I know what that's like. Yeah.
Did you go to college, John?
I don't want to study anymore college.
I want to study this thing. Mm-Hmm.
You know, I want to be a, a different, I want
to take a different path.
Mm-Hmm.
I love that. I I fully support that. Yeah.
I, um, I, I went to college.
Um, I did about, like, you know, five years
or so, I, uh, spent all the money
and I didn't actually graduate.
Um, and
because I had started a business, like towards the end years
of college with two of my friends,
and then when I, when I saw that, you know,
when you create a business, it was like, oh my gosh,
why am I focusing my time in college?
Mm-Hmm. Like, this is the job.
Even though the hardest part was my parents.
Like, they're, they were just very
kind of old school mindset.
So, you know, for, for the whole time they're like, John,
you need to finish school, school, school, school, school.
It's always been school.
They didn't prioritize anything else.
Um, but in my heart, I was like, I don't wanna do this.
Like, this is not for me.
Like, I want to go out there
and just do things I wanna experience.
I wanna make mistakes. Um,
and so my parents were always like
throwing like negativity at me.
Like, all businesses are gonna, you know,
99% of businesses fail.
Like, you need, you need a security
job, you need all this stuff.
And that was hard. That was really hard in the beginning.
'cause we're, we're always butting heads.
And then when they found out that I, I didn't graduate,
you know, that was a whole nother conversation.
Um, but, you know, in those early stages
starting, um, that journey, you, you make that choice.
Like you, like you braley like you, you make a choice.
You're like, this isn't for me.
And you have to trust in that choice, I think, um, no matter
what people say, parents, family, friends.
Yeah. If you know it to be true in your heart, in your gut,
that there's something else out there for me.
Like, that is your intuition.
That is your guide telling you
that you're meant to do other things.
Um, for some people, school's great.
You know, you wanna be a doctor, you wanna be a lawyer,
you want to be a nurse,
you wanna be a professional in some way,
that's what school's for.
But for creatives and for creatives
and entrepreneurs at spirit, there is no school right now
for those types of people.
I think this is the biggest problem with our society.
And maybe, I mean, this is for,
I'm talking us maybe even other around the world,
but there's never been, there's no school designed
for creative thinkers.
Creative thinkers who are more spatial,
who are more freethinking, who are more improvisational,
who are more unstructured.
Right. Like, the way that school's structured is to, like,
you memorize, and then you, you, you regurgitate.
Yeah. Uhhuh, like uhhuh and,
and for a creative person, like I have a DHD, um,
and my attention span is like this.
If I, if I lose interest on something,
you're not getting me to learn.
Like I'm not Yeah. In advance.
And, um, I'm sure a lot of people hear the same way.
Um, and I think like with more
and more creatives coming out,
or at least cre like I was telling this to somebody else is
back in like the nineties and stuff,
or like two thousands creativity, like, there,
there were only so few options to make it in the world
as a creative, you could, you'd have to be famous.
You know, you'd have to have already a lot of money,
you know, so you can pursue art and all that stuff.
Mm-Hmm. Um, but nowadays creativity is becoming,
like, you have creators, you have entrepreneurs,
you have musicians who are like taking it upon themselves
to take action to create the life that they wanna live.
Right. That wasn't, that wasn't possible before.
Maybe it was, but it wasn't like people,
it was very black and white.
It was like, no, that's not a possibility.
But now it's like you see kids in high school
who are like, crushing it.
You know what I mean?
Yeah. Yeah. What are you guys' thoughts on that?
Uh, I think I see some, uh, some,
my schools are making a lot of money
by using their social medias, right?
Mm-Hmm.
Almost there. Maybe almost downstairs.
Um, the power of the internet, man, you know,
we, I came into it.
I, I started my first business in like
20 11, 20 12, when
internet marketing was like, it was still, it was,
it was getting bigger, but it wasn't nearly
as big as it is now.
Um, yeah, of course.
And so at that time, like there was very few
resources that we could leverage, like tools and AI
and all that stuff didn't exist back then, right?
Um, it was a very kind of like, manual process.
And the people who had the information were like,
at the very, very top.
And, um, and fortunately,
like I got mentorship from somebody in the direct response
marketing space who was at the 1%.
And so when I had learned the ins
and outs of how direct response marketing works
and advertising works,
'cause I was, I was a graphic designer, it opened my eyes
to like, what, this is what's happening.
Like, I am, I am being manipulated.
You know, like, I didn't know that every,
every persuasion technique and every landing page
and every video had a formula.
And so with that being said, like, you know, that, that
to me was like the drug.
I was like, I'm hooked. You know,
if I know I can make this work,
I know if I can make money online, game over.
And, um, the moment you make your first sale online,
you just lose your mind.
'cause you're like,
how is this po I can't believe I
just made money doing nothing.
You know? Um, and so, you know, as a creative, you know,
obviously we had e-commerce businesses back then,
we had an agency.
Um, but now,
because like I've, I've learned
that creativity is really my strong suit.
Um, it's not running e-commerce businesses.
It's not running like brick and mortar businesses.
Like, at the end of the day, like, I've tried it all.
And what works best for me is creating, like, I love art,
I love telling stories.
I love, um, you know, ads like what we're doing right now.
Right. Um,
and I really believe like everyone has the ability
or opportunity to like generate a s**t ton of money
doing what they love as a creative, it's just the path has,
has hasn't been walked, um,
as frequent, as frequently as, let's say,
like someone in real estate
or someone in other types of businesses, right.
We are just at this time where more
and more people are walking that path
and showing that it's possible.
Right. And, um, I think
that's what's really inspiring, you know?
Um, even for me, considering the things that I've done
and the businesses that I've built, I get inspired by
people on Instagram and stuff, like, who are crushing it.
And I'm like, there like that, it's light at the end
of the tunnel, you know,
because there's always room to, to grow and improve.
But people who are in this community see the light.
You know? I think there's tons, you know, I just,
being here Braley I think is a really,
like, you're smart for doing that.
You know, you're taking that, that first step. Um, yeah.
I lost my mind when I, when I, uh,
got my salary online
because I couldn't believe
that I can make money online, you know?
Right. Yeah. It's, it's, it's incredible, man.
Like anywhere in the world, you know? Yeah.
And, um, and here's one thing that I wanted
to talk about too was, um, this is definitely something
that I want to create content around
or value around, is, like, I suffered from this
for a long time, is like, you know, valuing your worth.
You know, as a, as a creative, as a, as someone who, like,
who does services, I would always undervalue myself,
always undervalue my prices
and end up working more and making less.
And it is a very hard lesson for me to learn.
It took me, it took me many years.
Um, but there was always, like, in the back of my mind,
I don't know if you guys experienced this,
but maybe it's just like, the way I grew up
was like, you're not good enough.
Like, I, I, I dealt with imposter syndrome for a while,
and, um, just not being worthy, like, not feeling like,
and it really came, came down to this when I was younger,
and this is the problem with the schooling system, is that,
like, growing up, I was an artist.
I would draw things, I would create things,
I would make music.
Like I, I sucked at math.
You know, I'm not that great at reading.
I, these things that tr traditional academics would value
as important were the things I sucked at.
So with that, you know, from my parents' eyes, oh,
my son is not smart.
Or like, he's not academically gifted,
but when it came to making music, when it came to art,
when it came to, you know, video games,
like I was really good at that stuff.
Um, but however, as I grew up as an like, as an adult, the,
the trauma of that stuck with me.
And so it was this,
and that's how, uh, imposter syndrome essentially develops,
is when you're growing up
and your, your gifts aren't mirrored back to you,
which basically means like, if your parents don't say like,
amazing job, you know, it's so good.
Like giving you encouragement
and support for your gifts, um, is when
you kind of turn it around later on in life
and you become, like, you doubt yourself.
You know, you under undervalue yourself, you undercharge,
you do all these things because you just want
to like seek the approval of certain people.
Um, so that was my problem.
I don't know if anybody else experienced that.
Yeah, totally. Like, I, I relate to this so much as well.
I, I, I feel like even still, I have like,
there's certain time periods in my career.
Like, I've been working for four years, and every now
and then I feel like, uh, why,
why are these people paying me so much?
Like, especially when you look at other people doing the
same thing as well, and it's, oh,
why am I being paid so much?
And this is one thing that I've learned is like, just to
value yourself, but I still feel like is every now
and then I still have that, oh, I need
to value myself more.
Like I'm still undervaluing myself.
And I, I kinda shared the same journey with you as, uh, to,
I went to college, but I did not graduate as well.
And it's, it was the same for me that, oh,
I made my first money online.
I was like, oh, it blew my mind.
And just a few months later, I was making, uh,
more than both my parents combined.
Wow. Yeah.
This is me at 18, so it really blew my mind.
But like, I did a lot of mistakes as well.
It's kind of in the process of learning, is
I, I had a good job.
I was making good money, and at, at some point I burnt out.
I blew it all. Mm-Hmm. And then I was back to zero mm-Hmm.
And it was then kinda like, oh,
maybe I just got lucky with this.
Oh, I don't value myself now. Maybe I just got lucky.
I messed it up. And now it's so difficult.
And I think it was a depressing eight
to be here that, oh, you get to the top,
then you're at zero, and now you don't
have anything to work with.
And slowly building back up from there
and getting to, like, getting to the initial value
that you had when,
but, uh, you thought that, oh, you got lucky.
Hmm. Is, it was a challenging phase, I would say.
Wow. Very similar to me.
I didn't know you had the same story. Um, yeah.
Braley, how about you, man?
Uh, pardon me.
Uh, uh, I got the, I think I get right.
So, so, uh, every time I'm go to the school, uh, I say
to myself, I don't wanna do this anymore.
Mm-Hmm. So I find a job online
that can make money,
and then I apply on the websites
for, I think that's three months before I hired.
I didn't stop until I hired. Yeah.
And then, uh, yeah, I make lots of money today.
Yeah. Especially in,
you know, the countries that you live in.
Mm-Hmm. Like minimum wage there versus like
what people are willing to pay you from
around the world. Like, oh,
Geez. Yeah.
It's incredible. Um, yeah.
And that, that, that itself is a huge paradigm shift, um,
for parents, for people.
And, you know, it's almost like taboo to be like,
here's how much I'm making.
You know, versus someone who's just like working at a cash,
you know, at a, at the mall, you know?
Yeah. And, um,
and so one second.
I think that's one of the things that really changed
how I think about money, um, because what I was told
and what society wants to tell you about money is
that it's fixed, it's limited,
and yeah, you can only make a certain amount per hour.
Right. This hourly wage, um, is essentially, you know,
I charge per hour and stuff, but it's, it's not like,
but when you work at like McDonald's
or a fast food restaurant, you know,
I make 15 bucks an hour, 12 bucks an hour
or whatever, you have to,
it's like, there's no way you can get rich.
There's no way you can build a life that you wanna live.
Right. But they don't teach you, like,
school doesn't teach you this.
Right. You have to seek this outside.
And the reason why school doesn't wanna teach you this is
because they wanna keep you control.
They wanna limit human possibility
so that there's more control.
It's easier to control a society
when you don't give 'em all the information, you know,
and then you, you feed them the information that they want
to hear, that they, you want them
to hear, want them to believe.
But you know, where as a, as a globe,
as a human civilization, we are beginning to wake,
wake up to, Hey man, we are, we are more than
what society is, is presenting us.
As if that makes sense. Um, yeah.
But yeah, no, the, the money thing is, is huge.
Um, I lost it all too.
I think I, I, I talk about that in the course. Um, yeah.
But I, I'd be interested to know
what like everyone's goals are, you know,
because I've always been someone with like, big, big goals
of, you know, financial freedom
and time free freedom of time, you know,
experiences, all that stuff.
We'd love to hear kinda what you guys,
uh, like what your vision is.
Uh, for me it's, uh, uh, when I started to work my, like,
it's also funny because
how your goals change in a small amount of time
because, uh, I, I read this quote, it said that, oh,
you are lost because you are free.
Like, if you are free, uh,
and you have a lot of, uh, possibilities in front of you,
your goals constantly change.
I feel like, and for me, in the beginning I was like, oh,
I want to buy a buy my parents a house.
Mm-Hmm. Uh, and I want to have financial freedom.
I don't want to worry about money anymore.
And it was also a part
that played in me burning out is I wanted it fast.
Mm-Hmm. Like, why just need to get this done?
I need to retire by really quick.
And I just work super hard a few years
and I'll be good for my entire life.
But this is one thing that my mind has shifted on is,
uh, I don't want to do this anymore.
I don't want it fast as well.
Like when, when I burnt out
and I did not have work, I also realized that, oh, I'm kind
of bored now, not working.
If I retire by let's say 25
and I don't have to work anymore,
I don't think I'm gonna enjoy this anymore.
Mm-Hmm mm-Hmm. Like, I, I can't sit and do nothing.
Even, even if it's things that I like Mm-Hmm.
I can't not work and still be happy, if that makes sense.
I dunno how to put it, but it was sense.
And yeah, for now, my, my goal is to travel
and be able to work remote
and still not be restricted by my time,
is I don't want to be working full-time,
long hours every day.
And, uh, live a, like, because I want to travel.
I don't want to have this many hours
and travel kind of urgently everywhere
and be like, why don't,
even if I'm in in another country, I don't have time to visit.
Like, I've done this as well. Mm-Hmm.
That I wanted to, I'm in a new place I'm excited to visit
and then wife to work all day today.
So it's kinda my early goal for now is to being able to
not have a lot of work, being able to manage it efficiently
and also to explore the world.
I love it, man. I love it. Yeah.
I wanna touch on that in a second,
but braley, uh, what is your, what is your goal?
Uh, think same one. Yeah.
S so can you speak to the
Yeah, yeah. You can speak to,
I'll translate it.
Not on the, I'm 34. How old are you? Sparse?
I'm 21. 21. I just turned 21 2 months ago.
Congrats, man. I'm 20.
Oh, you're 20. Nice. Yeah, I love it. You guys are young.
So point on start case, uh, business.
How old was I when I started my business?
I was actually around your guys' age.
So 22, 23. Mm-Hmm.
Yeah. So I'm 34, 2012 minus for many years.
That is, so, yeah, I was about your guys' age.
Yeah, I was, before that I was just partying though.
I wasn't really doing anything, just drinking all the time.
Um,
I like it. I like your
setup, by the way.
Thanks. Thanks. Yeah.
I wanted to stand up because I feel like
I can get the energy moving a little bit more.
Um, but yeah.
Is there, yeah, I, I wanted to touch upon that, uh, sparse
in terms of the burnout and like, it seems like you've gone
through a big learning cycle in your own personal life
of when very similar to me, where I was, I wanted to hustle.
I had this hustle mentality of, you know, get it done.
I was taking Adderall,
which is like A-A-D-H-D medication to just like,
I know about this.
Yeah. You know, all types of substances to try
to make me more efficient and get more done in the time.
And I think that's just my natural energy is to like,
when I get into something,
I really wanna do everything I possibly can.
Um, and I would work, you know, 24, 48 hour days,
especially even in the early days
of like, my first businesses.
But even with econ, vids, like growing, that was like
a nonstop train.
Um, but yeah, just like you, I hit burnout.
Um, and then even later in life,
you know, I still hit burnout.
I was trying to kind of diagnose what that, what that meant,
but it really came down to like,
doing the things that I didn't want to do
and like trying to force myself to do those things.
Um, yeah. And then also trying, keeping people in my life
that weren't adding value
to my life were also like, burning me out.
Um, you know, sharing my energy with them
or like draining my energy with them.
That's a big one, is like, I had
to cut a lot of business partners.
I had to cut friends. I had to say no to a lot of clients.
Um, 'cause I was, I was, I was a yes man.
You know, I'd be like, oh yeah, let's do it. You know? Yeah.
Shame. Yeah. And I, I love collaborating.
Like, I love working with people,
but then I've found out like,
some people just don't hold their weight
or some people have different values than you.
Um, and that just leads to a whole nother sort of things.
Um, and I think this journey has been teaching me like,
like one that yeah, I am enough to do things on my own.
I don't need to be scared. Like, I don't need to partner up
with anybody to like, to be successful.
'cause I was like always afraid to do things on my own.
Um, but yeah, I think where you're at right now,
like you, you've, you've gained a lot of wisdom, um,
such a short amount of time.
So like, you know, you have, you know, if you, you get
to my age, you'll be in a much different position.
Yeah. Right. Got like, what, 14 years on you?
Is it 14? S**t? Yeah.
You're 34. 34. Yeah. Yeah. 13. It's interesting.
You, you have like an old soul.
You, you talk as if you're like my age. Um,
Don't, don't call me old John.
You have an old soul.
I'm saying, you've probably lived
many lifetimes before this.
Um, but yeah. That's good, man. Yeah.
On the topic of like time
and freedom, um, I think
in the stages of where we're at, depending on
where you're at in your life, um, there's always that like
skill acquisition, experience stage where,
you know, in the very beginning when you're just getting
into something like brayley, you're,
you're 10 months into this, right?
It's like, yeah, you have to acquire as many skills
and experiences as you can, um, in order to like, be able
to stand on your own two feet
and be like, Hey, I know what I'm doing.
Like I, I know I'm good at this.
Um, it doesn't matter, you know, if you're shooting content,
editing content, writing content, uh,
designing whatever creative thing it is, it's like, I think
that initial phase, you have
to just put in at least like a year's worth of work to
level yourself up.
And then you start to increase that by, okay,
how do I take this to the next level?
Do I charge double? Do I start a business?
Do I, you know, create courses?
Do I, um, try to get a percentage
of revenue from the work that I do?
Right? There's different paths that you can take, uh,
in order to expand your, your gifts by not just being like,
um, like an executor
or you could be a high level executor, right?
Because the way I see it as you can
work with a few and charge a lot.
You can work with a lot
and charge a little, which one sounds better?
Think the first one. Yeah. I think, yeah, of course.
I ticket. Yeah. And I've done both.
And I've, I've charged a little and I've done a lot.
And that's like no fun. Very tiring.
Um, as like somebody who's been in the industry
for a while, the thing that really, in terms of services,
like service industry, service businesses, the name
of the game is trust, respect,
and results.
Like I've learned, the people
who have paid me the most money are people
that are like it.
I didn't have to sell them on s**t. Yeah.
You know what I mean? The easiest
To work with Is, well, yeah.
It's like the, the client who, who charge you charge,
you know, 20 bucks for versus the,
the client you charge 200 bucks
for the $20 client is gonna take up like 80% of your time.
And then yeah. The higher ticket client
is gonna be like, okay, cool.
Where is it? All right, looks good.
Um, and I've learned like, it's just,
it's just what you attract.
Like people who are on that 7, 8, 9 figure level,
they're, they're not worried about the
details of that kind of stuff.
Um, and they're much more mature in their businesses
and in their life because in order to get to that point,
you have had to go through a lot.
You know, a, you know, millionaires don't just like come out
of thin air, um, or high playing clients
or successful people just don't like, you have to earn it.
Right? And so you develop an understanding, a trust,
an intuition, um, confidence, all these things.
And then when you work with somebody, like for me,
what I'm looking for in people, it's like I'm looking
for people that I can trust and that share vision
and that who are autonomous
and who know who can collaborate with me.
Um, and then people at the lower end
who are just getting started are usually in like, the realm
of fear and doubt and uncertainty.
And is this gonna work?
Um, I don't know if da, da da this and I don't know that.
And, um, are you gonna get back to me in time?
Like, there's a lot of, a lot of fear in, in people.
'cause they haven't done it, they haven't gone through it.
And so they're putting a lot of this trust, you know,
and they have very fewer resources as well.
So if they lose out on 20 bucks,
it could be the end of the world.
Versus someone who loses out on two 2000 be like,
eh, you know, not a big deal.
We'll make it up. So the biggest thing I've learned is
that trust, like developing a really strong relationship
with the people who you work for, those are the people
who are gonna keep paying you time and time again
and open you up to other opportunities.
Uh, and also referrals.
Like, I don't know how many times I've been referred to like
other eight, nine figure companies who are like,
Hey, dude, John does this.
He's a really good guy. You should work with him.
You know, like that's the best form of recommendation.
Like that's the best form of marketing is when someone
who already is very successful recommends you, you know?
Um, so I don't know if you guys are already doing that.
I'm sure you are, but that's just based on my experience.
Yeah. Same. Like, my biggest advice to you, Brady, as well
as a freelancer, is trust
and building relationships with people.
Even some people that you don't enjoy working with the most.
It's good to keep the relationship, leave them happy,
is like, I get so many countless referrals now
is some guy I worked with three,
four months ago can suddenly show up that I have a friend
who needs something similar.
Mm-Hmm. Can you get on this?
And like, I, it's, it's so powerful the power of referral.
Yeah. Thanks for that.
Uh, I think I'm making a good relationship
with my boss right now.
Awesome. It's awesome, man.
It's, uh, it's powerful stuff.
And I think what I'm learning is by
creating this community of other creatives, I realize
that I'm not the only one on this.
I'm not the only one experiencing these things. Yeah.
In fact, like all
of us are experiencing very similar things.
And I think one of the positions that I'm in right now
is like, one thing that I really want to
put more emphasis
and time into is really like strengthening the creative
community of what we do.
Because all this time that I've been doing it,
I felt like I've been alone.
I felt like nobody understood me.
Nobody has, like, no one is as passionate about it as me.
Even my own employees, like aren't
as passionate about video ads
and direct response marketing as I am.
And so it, it gets to a point where you're like, all right,
so what am I doing this for?
You know? There's gotta be other people out there
who like this as much as me.
Yeah. Um, so yeah,
I think I'm at this point where I want to, I want
to bring together a lot of those people
where we can all truly level up and um,
and, and, and, and share our value and experiences together.
'cause like what you're telling me, braley and,
and sparse, like, I'm like, dude, we,
we walked the same path
and just like I was saying in the very beginning of school,
not having this, this path,
it's like we are creating it right now.
Right? We are, we are literally
paving the way we're pioneering what it, what it takes
to be the people like us to make it in this world.
And it's not a perfect road, but if we can share our journey
and experiences and lessons
and wisdom with other people,
then other people have the same opportunity as you
and then create more opportunity
for other people in the space.
And that's the one thing that like really gets me excited
because it's something
that I wish I had when I was just
starting out. You know what I mean?
Yeah. Yeah.
I think I get the best choice
to just discuss because I think it's really good
and keeping me excited about creating
more video ads.
I love it. Love it.
Well, uh, that's the thing
because what makes this this world work
is, is money, right?
Um, video ads is the quickest way
to make money, in my opinion.
Because even when you're an influencer
or like, you know, when you have a ton of followers
or whatever, and, and brands are coming to you,
they're seeking ads, they're looking for content
that they can advertise.
Everything is advertising.
Everything that makes dollars is advertising.
Think of Super Bowl, think of movies, think
of, you know what I mean?
Yeah. Like you're in the best place to be to make money
because there's so much advertising needed.
And I believe that there's so much,
and there's very little advertisers, video ad creatives,
video ad editors there.
There's such a high demand for like good quality ones
and there's very little, and
there's very little training around it. So Yeah. And it's
Easy to sell as well.
Like it's directly, it's something that is,
that you can measure directly
Exactly. Of like
YouTube videos and stuff.
It's true. Yeah. You, you can get a direct result right,
right there and there, and it's very easy
to measure your performance.
Um, and it's like, then you can really
leverage that as social proof for yourself. Um, yeah.
That makes it easy to sell to other people.
Yep. Yep.
And with, you know, I think
what I've learned too is businesses will pay top dollar
for top talent if you can get the results.
Um, yeah.
And it doesn't matter where you are at in the
world, you know what I mean?
It's like Philippines, India, wherever, you know,
it's like you can charge American dollars.
Like why not? You know?
I think that's just a limiting belief of like, yeah,
if you're, if you are just as good, if not better charge,
charge that much because that's what you're worth.
You know? Because the way I see it is, you know,
let's say you pay me a couple thousand dollars,
but I make you tens of thousands of dollars.
It's no, no brainer trending. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Easy.
It's the, it's what ha what's
right, what's happening right now.
And what's been happening is that companies
and brands will pay tens of thousands of dollars
to get video and then make nothing back.
And this is because like the commercial industry is like
that, where I, I spent $15,000 on a, on a commercial
that I never even launched.
And it was like, it's asked backwards.
Like, you need to be paying, you need to be testing,
and you need to be, you know, split testing all this stuff
before you commit to anything like that.
But a lot of people think that if I just spend more money
on video production and commercials, it's guaranteed,
but it's like, so not true.
Um, so we're in this position of like performance marketers
to really kinda like be in a, be in a much stronger position
where, Hey, if I can get you results, here's
what I'll expect back.
Like, you can, I just had this conversation with a client,
I was like, Hey, look, I've,
I've delivered results in your business, um, many times,
and now you're in this position where you need me again.
And I was like, the only way that I'm gonna be able to
prioritize this is if you double my rate.
Or as the business grows, I'm, my income is also growing
with the business because,
and I've talked about this in the past, is
if they remove you from the business, the business fails.
This is such an important thing to remember, to realize
as a creative, you are so required
to make the business grow.
But right now, society
and how the industry is, is like,
they're not prioritizing creatives
and creative people as the, the,
the fuel that gets results.
But if you remove that person, you're left with nothing.
You, you, you can't move the business forward.
You can remove email, you can remove, um, you know,
you can remove other things from the business,
but if the creative is gone,
you're not gonna have any new business coming in.
And so that is your, your point of leverage if you were ever
to get to that point of like negotiating,
especially if you have the results to back it, um,
in the beginning, obviously like kinda work, work, work
until you can produce those results.
But when you get to that point,
the business owner's gonna be like, oh s**t, man.
Like, you're right. Like, all right, let's do it.
You know, I need you just like badly.
I need you more than you need me, kind of thing.
That's the position that you want to be in.
Yeah. Well, that's amazing, man.
Um, well, do you have any other questions braley for me
before I, we wrap this call up?
Uh, what's your best advice
to value?
Value? Myself, I
It's your best advice to value yourself. Yeah.
As a creative, That's a good question. Um,
Actually when, actually I may,
I said in 10 months here Mm-Hmm.
But can I, can I, how do I set my
value at high value and can make my salary double?
But
Yeah, so there's a couple things.
Sparse. Go ahead. You wanna start with that?
Yeah, sure. So I, I was just gonna say that I,
I was thinking about this
and it's, uh, what you said, uh, about doubling your rate
or asking for a split in revenue
or to being able to go up to a client
and be like, okay, to prioritize this,
I need more money from you.
Because you always have the feeling of, oh,
they can just hire somebody else if this doesn't align
and I don't want to risk this for it.
Yeah. And at the same time, it is also like,
it's difficult to have this before you have the results,
but it is also for you, yourself
to look at your own results.
It's difficult to value yourself, so you kind of have
to look at yourself from a third perspective
and see that way.
Like for me, what helped was when I was editing videos,
and at some point I started an agency which failed low,
but when I was hiring other editors,
I realized all the pain points
that you have when you hire an editor.
Like you see 90% of people there, it's difficult to work
with them, especially at the lower entity that I was working
with was I, I was like, oh, I'm doing
so much better than this.
And this allowed me to have a bigger perspective on, okay,
what, what is my value?
But yeah, it's funny that, uh, to
fee for yourself, even if you have the results
to value yourself,
because you are not never gonna reach that number.
Like, you always want to keep growing. Of course.
I think, yeah, to touch on that, something
that I've recently, um,
because I dealt with this, like I dealt with that insecurity
for a long time, um, really comes down to insecurity.
Um, like not valuing yourself
because you're insecure about your gifts, um,
because you weren't, you weren't necessarily praised
for them, you weren't acknowledged for them, you resources
and time and love was not put into them.
At least that's how I, it was for me.
Um, at the, at the core level
of valuing yourself really comes down
to like loving yourself.
Um, and so how this, how I did this,
and this is maybe beyond like what we're,
what we're talking about, but like healing my traumas.
Um, and basically like
channeling, medi meditating
to the point in my childhood when I felt like I,
you know, was getting yelled at my parents
or not supported by my parents and like forgiving them
and like talking to my inner child saying
like, Hey, everything's gonna be fine.
Everything, you're okay, you're talented.
Like, it's, it's having compassion for yourself. Hey man.
Like I literally, 'cause I have
a, I have a, I have two kids.
I have a four-year-old and a three-year-old.
And I see myself in the four-year-old,
he's exactly like me, exactly.
Sensitive, creative, all these things.
And I think back to when I was his age
and I wasn't being supported, like I just think back
to him and I put myself in his position, I just,
just give him a big hug, hug
and tell him, Hey man, you're super talented.
You are so gifted, you're so creative.
You're, you're gonna do amazing things.
Those are the things that I wasn't told, like growing up.
And so it's like when, if you ever
feel down on yourself, it's usually
because you didn't get that love.
And you have to be that love for yourself in order
to heal yourself from that.
Um, and then once you get through that,
then it's really just acquiring as much experience
as you can to build up the confidence
to say, I know what I'm doing.
I know I can repeat this success.
And when you can, when you can show that in one,
even just one client, then you can start to
be like, Hey, this is what I've done, here's what I charge.
And you can slowly, incrementally, incrementally start
to ask for more because you have the proof to show it off.
Yeah, it makes sense. Yeah.
All right guys, I'm gonna wrap it up there,
but it was, uh, it was a good call.
I love the direction that this one went.
I'm very big on personal development
and all that stuff, so thanks
for jumping on the call Braley,
and um, if you have any questions, just reach out
and uh, hopefully we'll see you on the next one, man.
Hey, I'm gonna, Hey bars. Hello.
Yeah. So, Uh, can we just have a,
uh, meet sometime so we can share our,
our thoughts and ideas? Yeah,
Yeah, totally do.
Alright, thank you. I'm gonna hit you up on Slack.
Great idea. I love it man. Okay guys.
Appreciate you both and um, I'll talk to you guys soon.
Talk soon. Thank you you guys. Bye.